Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/ashleyblackmon-ms-fnp-c-ba93097 (LinkedIn) uaprn.org (Company)

Top Skills
Critical Care
Nursing
ICU

Ashley Blackmon MS, FNP-C

Vice President for United Advanced Practice Registered Nurses, UAPRN GA

Greater Atlanta Area

Summary

Advanced Heart Failure and Heart Transplant at Piedmont Atlanta Hospital/ Samsky Advanced Heart Failure Clinic.

Past work experience in Gastroenterology, Family and Urgent Care, Pediatrics, Part Time Instructor at Georgia State University in the Family Nurse Practitioner program. Former nursing experience in trauma ICU, med-surg and neuro ICU, pharmaceutical nurse research.

Experience

United Advanced Practice Registered Nurses Vice President January 2018 - Present (2 years 5 months) State of Georgia

Volunteer officer at the state level non-profit organization to help empower Advanced Practice Registered Nurses through education, networking, and political advocacy.

Piedmont Heart Institute
Advanced Heart Failure Nurse Practitioner
May 2015 - Present (5 years 1 month)
Atlanta, GA

Managing inpatient advanced heart failure patients. This includes pre- and post- heart transplant or LVAD patients as well as palliative care patients.

Georgia State University Clinical Supervisor, Part Time Instructor August 2015 - December 2016 (1 year 5 months) Greater Atlanta Area

Guest lectured on EKG interpretation at the graduate nurse practitioner level. Reviewed work of 7-9 students, gave feedback on SOAP notes and clinical experience, then did clinic site visits to watch how students assessed, diagnosed, and treated patients.

Digestive Healthcare of Georgia Gastroenterology Nurse Practitioner March 2013 - May 2015 (2 years 3 months)

Piedmont Atlanta

Taking care of inpatient acute care, intensive care, and emergency department patients in consultation and follow up for a gastroenterology specialty group. Performed admissions, discharges, and assist in surgical procedures such as PEG tube placements (percutaneous endoscopy gastric).

Family Nurse Practitioner FNP-C July 2012 - March 2013 (9 months) Eagle's Landing Family Practice

I functioned independently as a family nurse practitioner seeing 4 years old and up in a fast paced environment. I also documented my own ICD-9 codes/billing. I performed many urgent care functions such as interpreting radiographs, giving IV fluids for mildly dehydrated patients, and suturing.

Georgia State University 2 years 6 months

Graduate Teaching Assistant and Student August 2010 - June 2012 (1 year 11 months)

Assist with questions and lectures in the Advanced Pathophysiology graduate nursing class. Lead review sessions and write practice questions. Independent research related to the course.

Family Nurse Practitioner Student January 2010 - May 2012 (2 years 5 months)

Atlanta Medical Center

6 years

Staff Relief RN, CCRN August 2010 - December 2011 (1 year 5 months)

Critical Care Nurse

March 2006 - December 2011 (5 years 10 months)

Assess, manage care and maintain confidentiality of

Assess, manage care and maintain confidentiality of patients in a trauma critical care environment. Patient and family education and care in a stressful environment. Run complex machinery, good time management skills and fast learner. Certifications: BLS, ACLS, ASLS, PALS, TNCC, CCRN.

Staff Nurse, ICU

January 2006 - December 2011 (6 years)

Implement patient care up to 2 critically ill patients.

Trained in all areas of ICU (surgical, vascular, cardiac, neurology).

Properly conducts trauma, surgical and medical admissions.

Appropriately monitors patient's status and notifies physicians of any changes.

Professionally interacts with other departments to provide comprehensive patient care.

Effectively interacts with and educates family members.

Performs in a preceptor position- instructor and advisor to other nurses.

Maintain and titrate multiple drips according to patient status.

Clinical skill sets include familiarity and monitoring of different machines such as: CRRT, cardiac output monitors, VIA (ABG) monitor, ventriculostomy drains and ICP monitors.

Performs comprehensive systematic patient assessments in accordance with scope of practice and policies and procedures.

Surface interpretation of EKG's and rhythm strips within ACLS and CCRN parameters

Maintain patient confidentiality in a busy environment.

Effective time management of patient assessments and therapies.

Altea Therapeutics

Clinic Research Nurse

January 2007 - March 2010 (3 years 3 months)

Maintain patient confidentiality in a research environment

Titrate medication drips according to research parameters

Maintain thorough and accurate documentation according the research protocols

Perform vital signs, EKGs, and IV placements

Perform assessments as needed of medication administration sites and patient needs

Assisting Research Coordinators with paperwork and gathering TEWL data.

Linda Vista, Guatemala

Clinic nurse

June 2006 - August 2006 (3 months)

First aid resource during youth soccer camps.

Blood pressure and medication review with patients.

Reinforcing education provided by local clinic and physicians.

2003-2006

Emergency Room Technician
June 2003 - July 2006 (3 years 2 months)

Assisting nursing staff in care of patients through admissions, bathing, placing in rooms, taking and documenting vital signs.

Starting IV's.

Placing foley catheters using sterile technique per physician request.

Placing temporary splints.

Assisting physicians with sterile procedures such as I&D, suture placement, chest tube placement and intubation.

Performing EKG's

Assisting with CPR in BLS parameters.

Spalding Regional Medical Center ER Technician

LIX recimiolari

June 2003 - June 2006 (3 years 1 month)

Start IV's, place foley catheters, assist with triage, take vital signs, EKG's, keep room stocked.

Education

Georgia State University

Bachelor of Science, Nursing · (2010 - 2012)

Georgia State University

BSN, Nursing · (2004 - 2006)

Gordon State College (official)

Associates of Science; Involved, Physician Assistant; student

counseling · (2000 - 2003)